

MAYUR SOLANKI

- Ahmedabad, India 382210
- +919726018106
- mayur.solanki003@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Passionate Public Health worker with more than 10 years of experience in multiple public health projects. During all these years I got precious opportunity working in different role from grass root level to state unit office. My work helped me to learn problem solving methods, mid-level management, innovative ways of team building, techniques of supportive supervision and mentorship. During all these years learned about the advocacy with the government departments, developing network with the various stake holders and community consultation.

EXPERIENCE

STATE PROJECT COORDINATOR, 05/2021 - Current *Alliance HIV/AIDS India*, Ahmedabad, India

- Since Private Sector Engagement Project newly launched in Gujarat State, established it in last two years.
- Brought all main stake holders Indian Medical association, District IMA Bodies, Management of Private Medical colleges, Gujarat State AIDS Control Societyofficers on board, educated them about project deliverables with series of engagements and numbers of sensitization programs.
- Initiated communication with all Private Medical colleges of state to adhere National Medical commission Norms and start ART (Anti Retro Viral Therapy) Centreto provide free medical services to HIV and TB patients.
- Demonstrated coordination between State AIDS Control Society and Private Medical colleges to set up ART Centre in PPP (Public Private Partnership) mode.
- Facilitated Feasibility assessment to begin ART Centre in Private Medical colleges, provided technical assistance after ART Centre start in facility.
- Mentored government ART Centers which were identified as "SPECIAL ART CENTRE".
- Ensured "SPECIAL ART CENTRE" reach to green color in score card from Red color in six months of time.
- Oriented Private ARV treatment providers to report to GSACS on quarterly basis.
- Arranged Continued medical education (CME) sessions in Private Medical collegesto sensitize Medical and Para medical staff about ART services.
- Worked closely with the Care, support & Treatment division of the Gujarat StateAIDS Control Society.

PROGRAMME OFFICER, 04/2019 - 04/2021

Public health foundation of INDIA, Bhavnagar, India

- Provided supportive supervision to NGOs implementing HIV/ AIDS project under Gujarat State AIDS Control Society as Technical officer of Technical support unit.
- Build the capacity of counselor to deliver effective counseling on behavior change communication.
- Facilitated induction training of newly recruited staff of NGO or transitioned NGO.
- Ensured that NGO utilize allotted budget in time as per guideline.
- Conducted field visits with NGO staff to meet end users and taken their feedback about project benefits availability to them.
- Developed NGOs' network with other health facilities of districts.
- Monitored hospitals associated with NGO to provide HIV/ STI related services and make sure that they function as per National AIDS Control organization (NACO) guideline
- Ensured that all NGO successfully passed NACO on site review in every two years
- Monitored NGOs' Out-reach workers IPC which they are conducting among the target group to

PROGRAM OFFICER, 12/2015 - 04/2019

SAATHII, Ahmedabad, India

- Handled the overall implementation of prevention of parent to child transmission of HIV (PPTCT) project in four districts with small team of Five field Coordinators.
- Consulted Private Doctor to enroll their hospital with The Gujarat State AIDS Control Society (GSACS) reporting system.
- Facilitated MOU signing procedure between Private Hospital and GSACS.
- Co-ordinate handholding training of newly involve hospital staff with nearest government HCTC facility (HIV Counselling & Testing Centre).
- Conducted hospital visit to ensure that they maintain record as per National AIDS Control Program guideline.
- Follow up with hospitals for timely reporting and reporting app installation.
- Organized CME with Private Doctors to orient them about prevention of parent to child transmission of HIV (PPTCT) program and importance of reporting.
- Planned Joint Visit with project coordinators to understand field challenges and guide them accordingly.
- Prepared salary of statements of field coordinators and forwarded for salary release.
- Monitored field coordinators activities, make sure that they work in line with their planning and align to project goals.
- Coordination done with NHM (National health mission) staff to organize the sensitization program of PHC (Primary health Centers) medical officers about PPTCT.
- Follow up done with the PHC whoever not performing ANC (Antenatal) HIV testing.

COUNCELLOD 12/2014 10/2015

COUNSELLOR, 12/2014 - 10/2015

Chuval Gram Vikas Trust, Ahmedabad, India

- Provided counselling about behavior change communication to vulnerable group who are having risk of acquiring HIV.
- Organized health camp at various project locations for the health checkup of key population.
- Coordination done with the different hospitals whichever tied up with project in PPP Mode for the regular medical checkup of targeted communities.
- Worked closely with the Ahmedabad municipal corporation (AMC) Mobile ICTC vane & CHC to provide HIV testing service at project localities.
- Kept follow up with ART centers for the regulars ARV medicine provision to HIV

positive patients of among project community.

- Established network with National TB elimination program (NTEP), National Hepatitis Viral Control program (NVHCP) for related service provision to key population.
- Conducted field visit with the outreach worker at project locations.
- Demonstrated IPC (intra personal communication) among the target group.

COUNSELLOR, 06/2013 - 05/2014

Parishram Parimal trust, Ahmedabad, India

- Provided counselling about behavior change communication to vulnerable group who are having risk of acquiring HIV.
- Organized Health camp and provide medical check-up services to the Migrant community of GIDC VATVA.
- Coordination done with the different hospitals whichever tied up with project in PPP Mode for the regular medical check-up of targeted communities.
- Worked closely with the Ahmedabad municipal corporation (AMC) Mobile ICTC vaan & CHC to provide HIV testing service at project localities.
- Kept follow up with ART centers for the regulars ARV medicine provision to HIV positive patients of among project community.
- Established network with National TB elimination program (NTEP), National Hepatitis Viral Control program (NVHCP) for related service provision to key population.
- Conducted field visit with the outreach worker at project locations.
- •Demonstrated IPC (intra personal communication) among the target group.

SKILLS

- Ability to work under pressure
- Flexibility & Adaptability

- interpersonal communication
- Microsoft office

EDUCATION

Bhavnagar University, Bhavnagar, GJ, 2013 **Master of Social Work: Social scicence**

Post Graduate 55.18

.....

Sardar Patel University, Anand, GJ, 2011 Bachelor of Arts: English Literature

REFFERANCES

Dr. Dhanikachalam

Senior Program Manager Aliiance India, New Delhi 9543230917

Dr. Janak Soni

Joint Director

Care Support Treatment Division - GSACS
9428812110